《斯巴达克斯：血与沙》
《娼妓》
啊 该死的
Ah, fuck.
都两周了 这个烙印还痛死人
Two weeks and the mark's still raw as a whore's cunt.
哎 我也有相同的烙印啊 兄弟
Argh, I bear the same mark, brother.
我才不会找这种下三滥的借口
Without pissing about it.
哈 哈 哈 哈
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
你每次攻击过后 就疏于防守
You lower your guard after each assault.
待会儿 我就让你尝尝我的厉害
I shall see it raised then.
你的命是我的了
Your head is mine.
我该怎样享受呢？
How shall I mount it?
你今天身手挺灵活嘛
You move well today.
你却大失水准
You do not.
在想什么呢？
What distracts you?
我让Ashur送了一封信给Aurelia
I had Ashur send a letter to Aurelia.
可是一周过去了 毫无回音
A week past now, and no reply.
你希望能有啥不同？
You expect different?
被丈夫骂作婊子的女人
A woman seldom rushes back to the husband
会回心转意才怪
who calls her whore.
我没说过这话
I said no such thing.
至少口头上没说过
Not in words.
那是封忏悔信
The letter was contrite.
我承认 当我听到她怀孕的时候
I admitted I reacted poorly
我的举止很粗暴
to the news of her being with child.
所以她让你一尝等待之苦
And now she makes you wait.
女人常用这招 来惩罚做了傻事的我们
The way women punish us for being fools.
别想这档子事了
Strike it from your mind.
否则你真要人头落地了
Or find your brains upon the sand.
这些面具真是精美绝伦
These are exquisite.
没错 它们可是家传之宝
Yes, they've been in the family for generations.
你经常做这种安排？
So this sort of arrangement happens often?
- 不 - 嗯
- No. - Um.
但是 有客人提出请求时
But when such a request is made,
我们只会提供最佳服务
one must be prepared to offer only the finest quality.
在这点上 Batiatus家族做得可圈可点
The House of Batiatus does not fall short in that regard.
我看 就这个吧
This one, I think.
啊 Diana 狩猎女神
Ah, Diana, the Goddess of the Hunt.
眼光真不错
A fine choice.
你觉得她会批准吗？
Do you think she would approve?
当Actaeon看见她在洗澡时
When Actaeon saw her bathing,
她把这可怜的家伙变成了一头鹿
she turned the poor bastard into a stag
还唆使他自己的狗去咬他
and set his own dogs upon him.
哦 多好啊 你也可以
Oh, how fitting then, that you should have
养一头自己的鹿来玩啊
a stag of your own to play with.
你有主意了吗？
Have you decided?
只有一个男人
There is only one man I would invite
让我愿意甘冒此险
such peril to know.
他就是斯巴达克斯
I will have Spartacus.
战神
The champion,
当然该是他
of course.
有问题吗？
Is that a problem?
多加点钱都行
If more coin is required.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
当然没问题 Marcus Crassus的表亲 自然值得
No the cousin to Marcus Crassus deserves
享有「死亡之影」的屠灭者
the Slayer of Theokoles himself,
价钱合理即可
at fair price.
哦 不是钱的问题
Oh, it is not the price that concerns.
退下
Psssh.
万一我丈夫知道 就不好了
If ever my husband were to hear of this.
世上没有
The gods themselves would have to
不透风的墙
whisper it in his ear.
我们在安排这方面的事情上
We take the utmost care with the delicate
总是力求谨慎
nature of these arrangements.
面具能确保你身份不外泄
The mask ensures anonymity,
但你也必须对自己负责
but you must also do your part.
严格保密
Tell no one.
约定时间要准时到达
Arrive exactly at the appointed time,
不要带其他人
unencumbered.
连奴隶和侍从也不带？
Absent slaves or attendants?
就怕有人对你丈夫太过愚忠
Who would hold your husband's loyalty truer to value.
我会 呃 为你和我们的训练场
I would err, avoid complications,
尽量规避风险
for you and this ludus.
是Ilithyia啊
Ilithyia.
哦
Oh.
抱歉打扰
Apologies.
我来早了？
Am I early?
有事吗？
For what purpose?
是你请我来吃午餐的啊
You invited me to midday meal.
是吗？
Did you?
没错 可时间是明天啊
Yes. For tomorrow.
哦 是明天？
Oh, was it?
但愿我没打断什么重要的会谈啊
I pray I have not interrupted important proceedings.
哦 不 恰恰相反
Oh, no, on the contrary.
我们仅仅只是在谈论你
We were only just speaking about you
和你的角斗士
and your gladiator.
他叫什么名字？
What was his name?
那个凯尔特人…
The Celt…
叫Segovax
Segovax.
对 Segovax
Yes, Segovax.
真可惜
Pity.
或许下次你应该多买一些
Perhaps you should buy several next time.
直到掌握此中要领为止
Until you get the hang of it.
这个过程可不简单
It's a difficult process.
只有极少数人能熬到终极测试 能站到竞技场上的就更少了
Very few make it to the final test, still few the arena.
我丈夫只看得上最强者
My husband demands only the finest.
我们也是
As do we all.
抱歉 我得走了 我丈夫还等着我呢
Forgive my haste, but my own husband expects me.
期待我们下次的会面
I look forward to our next encounter.
她喜欢你
She favors you.
我也喜欢她
And I her.
想不到我还有牵线搭桥的作用
It warms the heart, to know my hands
这还真让人窝心
are responsible.
我真该好好感谢你
Then let me take them in gratitude.
你要多加小心
You should be more careful.
当心Licinia
With Licinia.
她来自上层社会
She's of a strata above your station,
当她情绪发生变化的时候
and will not hesitate to remind you of it
她可不会提醒你
the minute her mood shifts.
而且她喜怒无常
And it shifts frequently.
我跟这种人打多了交道 深谙此道
I am well versed in dealing with such people.
没问题就好
Of course you are.
那么 你要邀请我吗？
So, am I to be invited?
邀请？
Invited?
去干嘛？
To what?
参加化装舞会啊
To the masquerade.
你以为我没注意到
You think I did not notice the mask
她想藏起来的那张面具？
she was attempting to conceal?
你误会了
You're mistaken.
没有什么化装舞会
There is no masquerade.
她仅仅是想借Diana的面具
She merely wanted to borrow the visage of Diana.
尽量规避「风险」呢？
To avoid "complications"?
一个有钱贵妇跑到训练场来
A wealthy woman of status visiting a ludus.
急欲藏起面具 小声说着风险问题
Concealing masks and whispering of complications.
如果不让我了解内情的话
If I did not know better,
我会怀疑她这趟来
I would suspect intent
- 是想跟你手下某个角斗士苟合 - Ilithyia
- to fuck one of your gladiators. - Ilithyia.
这就是她此行的目的 对吧？
She is, isn't she?
哦 那个小婊子！
Oh, that little whore!
多放荡啊！
How positively depraved!
我答应她要小心行事的
I promised discretion,
你绝对不能把这事说出去
you must not breathe a word of this to anyone.
我才不会这样做
I would never think it.
你是我最好的朋友
You have been a most valued friend.
这是我们俩的小秘密
And this will be our little secret.
我可以掌控她的
I can control her.
Ilithyia么？
Ilithyia?
就像你对她和Segovax做的那样？
Like you did with her and Segovax?
她让自己的人 去谋杀斯巴达克斯
She had her own man make attempt on Spartacus,
就在我们的眼皮底下
under our very roof.
你还说能够掌控她
And you yet speak of control.
斯巴达克斯让她理智全无
Spartacus inflames her beyond reason.
可Licinia是另一码事
Licinia is a different matter.
即使是Ilithyia
Even Ilithyia has sense enough
也会怕Marcus Crassus表亲的报复
to fear reprisal from the cousin of Marcus Crassus.
嗯 她本来就该这样
Humph, as she should.
那个人金贵着呢！
That man shits gold!
在罗马 能有这个人当靠山
To have the favor of such an ally in Rome
跻身元老院 就指日可待了…
could pave my way to a seat in the curia…
还有个小难题
There is one small obstacle.
Licinia喜欢我们战神摸上去的感觉
Licinia favors the touch of our champion.
哈 斯巴达克斯？
Ha, Spartacus?
这算啥难题
That will not be difficult.
哦 他可是难缠得很
Oh, he's always difficult.
过去的确如此 现在绝对不会
In a past that no longer exists.
我一下令…
I shall command…
他就会乖乖听话
and it shall be done.
啊
Argh.
卡普亚战神驾到！
The Champion of Capua arrives!
把朱庇特吓得屁滚尿流
A man who so terrifies Jupiter
风起云涌 天降甘霖的人啊！
the clouds burst and the heavens weep!
我的荣耀完全是主人之功
My glory is but a reflection of my Dominus.
你个马屁精！
You flatter!
您对我好 我对您好
I return in kind.
还要多谢天神眷顾
And the gods take notice.
当我以为我们能更上一层楼时
Just when I thought we'd accrued every accolade,
上天又降下一重考验
yet another falls in our laps from the heavens.
Marcus Crassus的表亲 美丽的Licinia
Fair Licinia, cousin to Marcus Crassus himself,
想私下传召你
has personally requested you.
Crassus是谁？
Crassus?
共和国内最有钱的人
Richest man in the Republic.
真是无上荣幸
A great honor.
我的对手是谁？
Who's to be my opponent?
对手？！
Opponent?!
Licinia对你的角斗不感兴趣
Licinia has no interest in watching you fight.
她感兴趣的东西…
Her desires are of a more…
比较暧昧
intimate nature.
要我和她睡觉？
I am to lie with her?
还要让其他男人自愧不如
And shame all men who follow.
战神就得去做这些事？
Such things are asked of a champion?
没错
They are.
你有意见？
You have concern?
没有
No.
我是卡普亚的战神
I am the champion of Capua.
我会尽一切战神的职责
I shall perform all duties required of me.
好好满足她
Bring her to satisfaction.
我们的财运 会像你的鸡巴一样一飞冲天的
And see our fortunes rise along with your cock.
有何不适吗？
Is there discomfort?
没有
None.
我何时才能恢复训练？
When can I return to training?
事实上 你还能活下来
The fact that you yet walk among the living
这本身就是个奇迹了
is a marvel in itself.
还有多久？
How long?
一个星期
A week.
也或许两星期…
Maybe two…
明日吧
Tomorrow.
不行 这也太快了
No. It is much too soon.
明日
Tomorrow.
那就明日吧
Tomorrow, then.
美好的一天 耽延不来啊！
A glorious day, long in coming!
Crixus你！
Crixus!
起死回生了！
Risen from the dead!
而Ashur我 也终于摆脱束缚
And Ashur, finally freed of his shackles,
要再次持剑上阵了！
to take up sword again!
你 想恢复训练？
You would resume training?
作为一名角斗士？
As a gladiator?
我也烙有印记
I yet bear the mark.
也渴望与兄弟们一同出生入死
And long to stand with my brothers,
重新屹立于竞技沙场
once more upon the sands of the arena.
或许这次你该放聪明点
Perhaps this time you will have the sense
离我远一点
to stay out of my way.
把这破玩意从我腿上拿掉
Take this fucking thing off me.
快啊
Now.
他未加拒绝吗？
He gave you no pause?
没有
None.
我们的奴隶…
Our dog…
终于被驯服了…
is finally house broken…
你很明智…
You were wise…
放倒了他的女人…
to put down his bitch…
啊 哦 呃
Ohhh, oh, uh.
退下… 端些酒来
Leave… and send in some wine.
一切按计划进行
Everything comes to plan.
Licinia会对我们感激涕零
We shall have Licinia's wet gratitude,
也会传到Marcus Crassus的耳中去
and with it the ear of Marcus Crassus.
若是斯巴达克斯遵守承诺
If Spartacus performs as promised.
他的每一寸呼吸 都会
Every breath he takes is in service to
与家族荣耀同在
the glory of this house.
我知道他很愿意
I know he's willing.
可他已经很久没与女人上过床了
But its been many months since he last lay with a woman.
这样一来 他的激情怕是…
After such a time, his passion might be…
所存无几
all too brief.
呃 这可很糟糕啊
Well, that would prove unfortunate.
这种情况很容易避免
Yet easily avoidable,
若是斯巴达克斯在此之前
if Spartacus is presented opportunity
多多磨炼床上技巧…
to hone his skills beforehand…
你进错房间了
You have wandered to the wrong cell.
你不是斯巴达克斯吗？
Are you not Spartacus?
送雨的使者？
Bringer of Rain?
我是Mira
I am Mira.
我被派来慰劳你
I have been sent to please you.
你想做什么？
To what end?
不是为了给你带来欢愉嘛？
Is your pleasure not an end to itself?
我没工夫与你说笑
I do not care for games.
告诉我你的真实目的
Give your true purpose.
快说！
Find your tongue!
主人担心你
Domina fears that you've been too long
这么久没有上过女人
without a women.
怕你到时候无力支撑
That you will be unable to withhold your seed
不能满足那个罗马女人
long enough to please the Roman woman.
这种念头真令人不快
The notion offends me.
你也一样
As does your presence.
我不想要我吗？
You do not desire me?
我只想睡觉
I desire only sleep.
一夜无梦
And the absence of dreams.
天神赐予我力量
The gods grant me strength
挣脱枷锁 得以自由
to rip these fucking bars from their moorings.
我们愚蠢地以为 他们会保佑我们
We were fools to think they favor us.
我们至少还能站在一起
We yet share a roof.
若是主人把我卖掉 便不会这样了
It would not have happened if Dominus had sold me.
这还不足以证明我们的姻缘 是上天注定的吗？
Is that not proof that our union is favored?
眼睁睁地看着你 却无力拥有你
To have you, but not have you.
内心的伤痛难以愈合
It is a wound beyond healing.
一切皆会愈合
All wounds heal.
即使最深切的伤痛
Even the deepest.
其他人未曾经历过的切肤之痛
Would that they had never been inflicted.
你还不了解我的心意吗？
You would wish never to have known my heart?
战无不胜的高卢人回归了
The Undefeated Gaul returns.
或许他该选个新名字了
Perhaps it is time he chose a new name.
Crixus啊
Crixus.
看到你重返沙场 我情绪高昂
My spirit soars to see you again upon the sands.
我福大命大
The underworld would not have me.
注意！
Take note!
一位真正的战神重返我们的队伍！
A true champion rejoins the Brotherhood!
狗屁战神
Champion of ass and balls.
世间还能有第二个 像Crixus这样的男人么？
Has there ever been such a man as Crixus?
没有 主人
No, Domina.
从来都没有
There has not.
赞美众神 让他重新回归
Praise the gods for his return.
希望众神保佑他能取得更多的胜利
May they guide him to many more victories.
也保佑我们钱图无量
And our purse filled by such.
没错
Yes.
财源滚滚来啊
Filled to bursting.
你来和Duro练习
You will spar with Duro.
那个日耳曼人？
The German?
他竞技场都没进过啊
He has yet to step in the arena.
但你也久疏战阵
And you have been long absent.
通过和他对抗来慢慢提高
Prove yourself against the man and see advancement.
那么谁来和我Ashur练呢？
And who shall face Ashur?
可得小心选啊 我嗜血已久
Choose carefully, for I long for blood.
- 你能训练？- 没错
- You train? - I do.
谁告诉你的？
By whose word?
主人说过要让我
The Dominus himself promised
重新回到兄弟们之中
that I would rejoin the Brotherhood
只要我摆脱掉那该死的支架…
once I was freed from that fucking brace…
Ashur啊
Ashur.
过来一下
A word.
主人在喊他的小狗呢
The master calls his dog.
记得我和Hasdrubal的那场胜利么？
What of my victory over Hasdrubal?
我把他脑袋切成两半时 观众叫得多疯狂啊？
How the crowd roared when I cloved his head in two?
小小胜利 早就被遗忘了
A minor victory, long forgotten.
那和Kleitos的那场！
Kleitos, then!
- 或者… 赢Lysimachos的… - 都多久以前了
- Or… or Lysimachos… - All long ago.
你作为角斗士的日子 已经一去不复返了
Your days as a gladiator are past.
主人
Dominus.
我恳求您
I beg of you.
给我机会证明我还有用
Let me prove myself yet worthy.
你已经在竞技场之外
You already have.
证明过了
Outside of the arena.
你的狡诈比任何一个角斗士的剑都要锋利
Your cunning is sharper than any gladiator's sword.
我不会为了你愚蠢的自豪感 去冒险的
I would not risk it on errands of foolish pride.
你听懂了吗？
We in agreement?
好的 主人
Your will, Dominus.
那来谈谈正事吧
To business, then.
关于Solonius 我有些想法
I have had thoughts toward Solonius.
咱们市场的路上 边走边谈吧
I would discuss on the way to market.
你有没有发觉Crixus回归之后
Did you note any signs of discomfort
有什么不舒服的迹象？
as Crixus took the sand?
- 没有 主人 - 呃
- No, Domina. - Uh.
他很渴望重新夺回自己的位置
He's anxious to regain his place.
但我不希望他做过头
But I would not see him overreach,
也不希望他把伤痛藏起来
nor hide pain from his recovery.
如果你发现Crixus有什么事情瞒着我
If you notice Crixus attempting to conceal anything from me,
你要马上告诉我
you tell me immediately.
是 主人
Yes, Domina.
异性可能感觉不到
The opposite sex has no sense whatever
他们的极限是什么
when it comes to their limits.
必须一直监视他们
They must be constantly watched,
至少别让他们在做爱时受什么伤
least they harm themselves in the simple act of being men.
等等
Wait.
主人
Domina.
昨晚你和Spartacus过得怎么样？
How did you fare with Spartacus last night?
满足后的他 阳具是不是很壮观啊？
Was his cock of impressive size when engorged?
他要了你几次？
How many times did he have you?
啊？
Huh?
说话
Speak.
他不愿意要我
He would not have me.
他不愿意？
He would not?
是的 主人
No, Domina.
到现在你才来告诉我？
And yet you wait until now to tell me?
我怕您听了会不开心
I was afraid you would be displeased.
把衣服脱了
Take your dress off.
乳房 臀部还有阴部
Tits, ass and cunt.
看起来没有什么疾病或者畸形
All appear to be without disease or deformity.
这样看来问题并不出在肉体上
Which tells me the fault is not in the flesh,
而是出现在你心里
but in the bitch.
主人恕罪
Apologies, Domina.
今晚再去他的房间 一定要他和你做
Return to his cell tonight and I expect his cock in you.
不然你就永远别做了
Or you'll find a sword in its place.
啊
Ahhh.
这里又不是竞技场
This isn't the arena.
这整个世界就是我的竞技场 傻小子
The world is my arena, pup.
我要个真正的男人
Send me a man.
原地站好！
Stand down!
Agron你！
Agron!
还有Duro！
Duro!
够了
Enough.
你们负责处理这星期一半的粪便
Half rations for the remainder of the week.
要是敢再犯 我就要你们都滚去挖矿！
Test my patience again and I'll see you both to the mines!
Crixus又交了两个朋友啊
Crixus continues making friends.
还是没有你妻子的消息吗？
Yet no word from your wife?
目前还没有
None forthcoming,
我也没有多余的钱 给Ashur来送信了
and no more coin to pay Ashur for the service of letters.
如果你不专心训练的话
You will dishonor us,
我们就会蒙羞
if your mind is not on the games.
告诉那狗腿子 我来付钱
Tell the jackal I will cover the cost.
我会还你的
I will repay you.
快去
Quickly.
在他离开之前
Before he departs.
Ashur啊
Ashur.
你伙计跑的真快啊
Your man has run afoot.
或许该关心你真正的对手了
Perhaps you'd care for a real opponent.
你如此渴望再回去见医生吗？
Are you so eager to return to the Medicus?
Crixus啊
Crixus.
主人召见你
You are summoned.
马上
Soon.
啊 下去…
Uhh, get off…
啊
ahhh,
多玩一会儿
tarry a while.
你主人还在集市 而且
Your masters yet at market, and
Ilithyia还要过几个小时才来
Ilithyia's not expected for several hours.
呃 我的皮肤柔软吗？
Uh, is my skin not soft?
是的 主人
Yes, Domina.
我让奴隶们建了个牛奶浴池
I had the slaves draw a milk bath,
让我回想起 那曾经令你欢喜
recalling a time when it pleased you
我们一起度过的时光…
that we could afford such things…
噢 伤口还疼吗？
Oh, does it yet cause you pain?
不 主人
No, Domina.
我却心疼到无法说出口
I wish I could say the same.
看着如此完美的你 被死亡之影摧残
It was torture to see such perfection
真是心如刀割
marred by Theokoles.
当你跪倒在地…
When you fell to your knees…
那个巨人站在你的身后时…
And the giant was at your back…
我胸中的一颗心 被狠狠地揪起
My heart seized in my chest,
而后你看向主席台
Then you looked up to the pulvinus.
看向我
To me.
在生与死冻结的一刹那
What was of your mind,
你脑中在思量什么呢？
in that frozen moment between life and death?
得知一位女神对我的爱意
That I welcomed the afterlife,
我死而无憾
having know the love of a goddess.
你永远属于我 Crixus
You will always be mine, Crixus.
唯我专属
Mine alone.
5个袍子 花了我双倍的钱
Five sacks, for the price of ten.
这次要留心烘干 贱婊子
And see to it they are dryer this time, shit whore.
最后几个都发霉了
The last ones stank of mold.
别激动 Solonius
Do not churn, good Solonius.
到下一个收获季节
The thief will suffer
物价暴跌的时候 小贼自然有得受了
when prices plummet with the next harvest.
我祈祷他的老二也跟着阳痿
I pray his cock follows the decline.
他没拴住你？
You are left off leash?
我的主人在别墅
My master is at his villa.
我还有事情要去办
I yet have business to attend.
奉劝一句 留意身边信得过的人吧
And words, searching for receptive ears.
我的境况已有所转变
My situation has shifted.
你所谓的忠诚呢？
And with it, your loyalties?
正如你所说 Batiatus证明自己不值得如此
Batiatus proves himself unworthy, as you had divined.
这等蝼蚁 怎么能与真正的伟男子
Such base character seldom weighs
相提并论
the true worth of a man.
我认为你更胜一筹
I take it your scales are more in balance.
我握有价值重大的信息
I hold valuable news.
远超过上一次
Beyond the meager recompense you offered
你所付出的廉价报酬
when last we spoke.
我身边的手下多了…
I am surrounded by jackals…
这关系到你的生命安全
It concerns your life.
如果这也无法让你动心掏钱… 那算了
If that is no cause for you to loosen your purse… um.
等等
Wait.
你把我的骨头挑得一干二净
You have picked my bones clean.
说吧 赶在我把血肉收回来之前
Speak, before I reclaim the meat.
每一周的这个晚上
You fuck the whore Despoina
你都会操Despoina那个荡妇 是不是？
on this night every week, do you not?
你的消息之灵通 我早已如雷贯耳
You voice what is already well known to me.
嗯
Um.
换一个其他人去吧
Send another cock in your place.
否则你的脑袋就得跟着老二一起搬家
Or see it removed along with your head.
Batiatus想要动手对付我？
Batiatus moves against me?
我要去给他的代理付钱 看看命令执行得如何
I am to pay his agent, and see the order given.
我警告过你了
You've been warned.
我真不敢相信这华丽的变身
I really cannot believe the difference.
当我第一次拜访你家时
When I first visited your home,
我感受到的是一个 被迫居于此地的女人
I felt great sorrow for the woman forced
浓浓的悲伤
to live in such conditions.
看看如今的你
Now look at you.
白玉为床金做马
Surrounded by opulence
足以配得上 家族显赫的地位了
rivaling families of proper heritage.
不过是些小玩意儿
Trinkets merely,
和你的友谊相比 还是寒碜了些
not nearly so valuable as your friendship.
你最近交了许多新朋好友啊
You have many new friends of late.
你和Licinia看起来 彼此
You and Licinia seem quite at ease
相处融洽呢
with one another.
这要归功于你的引荐
Gratitude for the introduction.
想喝点酒还是…
Would you care for some wine or…
酒已经无法吸引我
Wine will not still my thoughts.
我只是随便开玩笑
I prattle on with pleasantries,
但你透露出关于Licinia的信息时
but I cannot pretend indifference
我无法视而不见
to what you revealed about Licinia.
我不曾透露过任何事
I revealed nothing.
你的结论过于仓促
You jumped to conclusions.
但有据可循
And landed on proper footing.
从那以后 我对任何事都提不起兴趣
Ever since, I can think of nothing else.
客气地说
With respect,
Licinia只关心自己
Licinia's passions are her own concern.
我可不会在意Licinia
My mind falls not to Licinia.
我脑中充斥的是下作的念头
It is filled with baser thoughts.
幻想着粗鲁的大手
The vision of brutish hands
在我身上肆意游走
being laid upon me.
在某种程度上来说 我丈夫的抚摸不具备如此的野性
in a manner quite lacking in my husband's touch.
我不该说出这些想法
I should not speak of such things.
我真令自己蒙羞
I dishonor myself.
你的欲望无可厚非 无需羞愧
Your desires should not shame you.
你是个女人
You are a woman.
我们女人的欲望如海
Our needs are vast.
我必须抹去这欲念
I must put my mind from it.
为了分散注意力吗？
To the purpose of distraction?
我更乐于分心其他的事情
Preferred to discovery.
这种事情会毁了我的丈夫
Such a thing would ruin my husband,
败坏我父亲的名望
and taint my father's name.
许多像我们这般地位的人 都声称担心这一点
Such concerns are voiced by all those who sample our wares.
除了Licinia 你还知道谁吗？
Can you name any, save Licinia?
我从未听说还有任何人
I have heard of none.
是啊 你没听说过
No. You have not.
我来给你安排吧？
Shall I make the arrangements?
请！
Yes!
你绝不会失望的
You will not be disappointed.
我能推荐Varro吗？
May I suggest Varro?
Varro啊？
Varro?
嗯 他太平庸
Uh, far too common.
而这个人必须值得冒险
The man must equal the risk.
他是你自己的欲望源泉
A fact well known by your own desires.
也是我愿意去分享的那个人…
Ones that I admittedly share…
主人…
Domina…
你这肮脏的奴隶 出去！
Get out you filthy slave!
哎呀！
Argh!
我双耳听到家里的暴动
My ears suggest a tempest,
一看 却他妈发现是老婆疯了！
but eyes reveal a wife gone fucking mad!
是的 好好瞧瞧Ilithyia这个惹祸精
Yes, well look to Ilithyia as the cause.
你又受到怎样新的蔑视
What new slights have prompted
引发如此破财的大爆发？
this costly eruption?
当她得知Licinia有一个角斗士床伴时
Her cunt overflows at the thought
她的私处就泛滥成灾了
of Licinia bedding a gladiator.
她要求同等的待遇
She demands equal treatment,
于是她将性欲发泄到Crixus身上！
so she set her lust on Crixus!
她的选择激怒了你？
And her choice droves you into rage?
并非她的选择
It's not her choice,
是她的傲慢举止惹怒了我
it is her manner that offends.
她企图用口中的甜言蜜语
Honey drips from her tongue,
掩饰对我们撕咬的
to conceal the bite of piss
切肤之痛
that she showers upon us.
那刻薄尖酸的味道再熟悉不过
The acrid taste is well familiar,
但我们要学会忍耐 直到获得她丈夫的赞助
but we must learn swallow it, along with our pride
那时我们将名利双收
until we have secured her husband's patronage.
Licinia已经为我们送来了Marcus Crassus
What need have we of Glaber,
我们对Glaber还能有何需求？
Licinia delivers us Marcus Crassus?
Crassus的价值无可争议
Crassus' wealth is undeniable,
但他目前只是空有议员的头衔
yet he but holds the rank of senator.
Glaber的副将职位可有分量得多
Glaber outweighs with that of Legatus.
对名利双收的渴望
The favor of both coin and title
将加速实现我们的雄心
would speed our ambitions.
为了抬高你 就要让我下跪？
To rise you would have me kneel?
总有一天 我们会给Ilithyia
One day soon we will give Ilithyia
好好上一节礼仪课
a lesson in manners.
但如今 现实需要我们将Crixus贡献于她
But for now, necessity dictates we give her Crixus.
就这么定了
Make the arrangements.
该死的高卢人…
Fucking Gaul…
想想别的吧
Turn your thoughts.
过不了多久我就会将他击败
I'll have at him soon enough.
你希望你的兄弟死掉吗？
You wish your brother dead?
谁放的狗屁？
Who speaks such a thing?
你的所作所为
Your actions.
我只想护得他周全
I only wish to protect him.
在每个角斗士
And who will do so in the arena,
都必须孤军奋战的竞技场 谁能做到呢？
where every man must stand alone?
你无能为力
You do him no favors.
你撒谎！
You lie!
Varro啊
Varro.
嘿 把你的谎言告诉他！
Hey. Tell him you lie!
我已按钱办事
I did what you paid me to do.
我找到他妻子的住处 但她不在那儿
I sought out his wife, but she was not there.
他儿子呢？
The boy?
空无一人
I found no one.
但是地面上有血迹…
But there were traces of blood on the floor and…
理智点！
Gain your senses!
杀了他
Kill 'im.
快啊
Come on.
守卫！
Guards!
铁链砸不烂的
They will not break.
我试过了
I have tried.
去和Batiatus谈谈
Speak to Batiatus.
谈什么呢？
Towards what purpose?
他能听进你说的话
You have his ear.
哪怕他让我离开这里一两天也好
If he would let me leave these walls for but a day or two.
他不会允许的
He would not allow it.
你都没试过 怎么知道？
You will not even make attempt?
只用锁链禁锢你 已经是侥幸了
You are fortunate only to be chained.
向主人提出这等请求
To petition Dominus with such insanity
只会招致更大的惩罚
would only provoke further punishment.
这样如何能解决问题？
How would that help your cause?
我想不清楚
My cause is lost.
Ashur只发现了血迹
Ashur found only blood.
没有尸体
No bodies.
也就是说 你妻儿也许
Which means your wife and child may
还活着
yet be living.
神啊 请惩罚我 饶了她们吧
The gods punish me, for failing them.
神才从来不理会傻瓜
The gods rarely take note of fools.
现在 别一味莽撞 也动下脑筋吧！
Now, pull head from ass and use it for once!
如果受到袭击 你妻儿要逃到哪去？
Where would your wife and boy flee, if set upon?
想想
Think.
是Naevia吗？
Naevia?
天色已晚
The hour is late.
你该回房间了
You should be in your cell.
我睡不着
I could not sleep.
我脑海中一直浮想着竞技场
My mind is full of thoughts of the arena.
尽情享受沙场的时光吧
Embrace the sands of time.
随着时间流逝 我相信
As they flow, I harbor no doubt
你将再次成为战神
you will again be a champion.
卡普亚已经有了自己的战神
Capua already has its champion.
斯巴达确实名副其实
Spartacus bears the title,
但我期待荣耀之人 重获战神之名
but I look towards a man of honor to regain it.
如果你珍爱生命…
If you value your life…
就不要吵醒角斗士
never awaken a gladiator.
求你了…
Please…
主人派我来…
Domina sent me…
从哪儿来 回哪儿去
Return the way you came.
你为什么要拒绝我？
Why do you refuse me?
我不诱人吗…
Am I not pleasing…
我不希望同奉命行事的女人
I have no desire to lie with a woman
同床共枕
who has been commanded to do so.
如果我不能服从命令
And what do you think will happen
你觉得将会怎么？
if I fail such a command?
那就留下吧
Stay then.
睡地上
On the floor.
就没什么我能
Is there nothing I can do
为卡普亚战神效劳的吗？
for the Champion of Capua?
我还真有个忙想要你帮
There is one desire I would have serviced.
如果你可以的话…
If you are able…
今早斯巴达爆发了啊
Spartacus breathes fire this morning.
我想知道原因
I wonder to the cause.
Mira啊
Mira.
你和我们战神的一夜春宵如何呢？
How did your evening pass with our champion?
他…
He made…
要了我很多次
many demands of me.
很多次啊？
Many demands, eh?
我们的色雷斯人准备好交欢了
Our Thracian is ready to stud.
我会为此特殊一夜精心安排的
I shall make arrangements for this very night.
而当太阳升起之时
And when the sun rises,
我们就有接近Marcus Crassus的机会了
we will have road to Marcus Crassus.
Ilithyia呢？她对Crixus感不感兴趣？
What of Ilithyia, and her desire for Crixus?
我已经计划妥当了
I've already set plans in motion.
小狗露出了牙齿
The pup bares his teeth.
毫无睡意吗？
Sleep did not come?
也不应该有
Nor is it deserved.
日落之时 就能拥抱美梦了
Embrace dreams when the sun falls.
我有消息了
I have news.
有关Aurelia的吗…
Aurelia…
还不是
Not yet.
但我已经派Mira
But I have dispatched Mira,
一名家奴 去找她了
one of the house slaves, to look for her.
还有你儿子
And your son.
这你怎么做到的？
How do you manage such a thing?
她被主人送来
She was sent by Domina.
让我为…
To prepare me for certain…
尽战神的职责而磨好枪
duties required of a champion.
所以现在 神都把女人抛给了你！
So the gods throw women at you, now!
啊！啊！
Ahh! Ahh!
你的状态回来了
Your form returns.
和Hamilcar一对吧
Pair with Hamilcar.
看起来Duro丢下她弟弟了
It appears Duro has lost his brother.
也比丢了脑袋要好
Better that than his head.
事成了吗？
It's done?
已经干掉Despoina那婊子了
The whore Despoina fucks no more.
当我撕烂她喉咙时 也干掉了操她的男人
Nor the man inside her when I slit her throat.
但那人不是Solonius
It was not Solonius.
呼
Phew.
我看的是谁的头？
Whose face do I look upon?
Kastor的
Kastor.
Solonius的一个手下
One of Solonius' men.
把这个带给Solonius
Send it to Solonius.
让他尝尝死里逃生的滋味
Let him savor the relief of escaping death.
现在
For the moment.
你将和一位正宗的罗马女人上床
You will be bedding a proper Roman woman.
她的地位 你遥不可攀
One far above your station.
说话小心点 别惹恼了她
Heed my words, that you not offend her.
是 主人
Yes, Domina.
什么也别说 也别出声
Speak not a word, nor make a sound,
留着力气享受
save one of pleasure.
听从她的吩咐
Follow her lead,
揣摩她的想法 积极地满足她
anticipate her desires then fulfill them. Vigorously.
是 主人
Yes, Domina.
在竞技场上 你是卡普亚的战神
In the arena, you are Champion of Capua.
但今晚 你不过是个普通奴隶
But tonight, you a common slave.
听从吩咐
To do as commanded.
都懂了吗？
Are we clear?
懂了 主人
We are clear, Domina.
她们会帮你安排妥当的
They will prepare you for the festivities.
等待召见吧
Wait until summoned.
拿最好的酒来
Fetch the best wine.
她过来的时候 要让我们的嘉宾能金枪不倒
I want our guest well plied when she arrives.
是的 主人
Domina.
您昨晚在哪？
Where were you last night?
我一直在等 差点被发现了
I waited almost to the point of detection.
我无法脱身
I could not break away.
我一直在服侍主人
I was tending to Domina.
是主人吗？
Domina?
还是今天我看见的那个 和你一起的守卫
Or maybe that guard I saw you with today.
你弄错了…
You are mistaken…
我可不是瞎子
I am not blind.
你却在摩挲他的胳膊
You were touching his arm
谈笑风生 而他注视你的眼神…
and laughing and the way he gazed at you…
要是你真没瞎的话 那你就该清楚地看到
If you are not blind, then you surely see
Hector对所有女人都是同样的眼神
that Hector gazes at all women in the same fashion.
我鸟都不鸟其他女人
I give no shit about other women.
你真丢我的脸
You shame me.
你自寻其辱 尽想着些虚构的东西
You shame yourself, with thoughts of imaginary slights.
我知道我看见了什么
I know what I saw.
没 你才没有！
No. You do not!
当然Hector也没有看到
and nor did Hector.
他的钥匙？
His key?
这才是我调笑他的意图
The purpose of my smile and touch.
他也只配得到这个
The only one he received.
我只能待一会儿
I have but a moment
就必须把主人的酒带回去
before I must return with Domina's wine.
好好利用 为曾有的想法道歉…
Use it to apologize for ever thinking…
你就是我的心脏…
You are my heart…
我再不会怀疑你了
I will never doubt the beating of it again.
哦 抱歉 Licinia
Oh, apologies, Licinia.
看起来 我们得等Idlithyia和斯巴达克斯
We appear to have arrived before Ilithyia's
做完之后才轮到你
finished with Spartacus.
不！
No!
守卫！
Guards!
哦
Oh,
这会不会在罗马的流言蜚语中风生水起啊
would this not set every tongue in Rome wagging.
Claudius Glaber副将的妻子！
The wife of Legatus Claudius Glaber!
跟斯巴达克斯交欢
Fucking Spartacus,
而此人还曾经差点毁掉他！
the man that nearly ruined him!
是个丑闻 不是吗？
It is a scandal, is it not?
是我听过的最大丑闻啊
The most splendid I have ever heard.
别笑了！
Stop laughing!
别再笑了！
Stop Laughing!
Ilithyia啊！
Ilithyia!
你到底在想些什么？
What were you thinking?
她处处蔑视我
She slights me at every turn.
我只想教训她一顿
I wished only to teach her a lesson.
让她和斯巴达克斯干么？
By pairing her with Spartacus?
如果我丈夫不能维护我的荣耀
If my husband will not defend my honor,
就只好我自己来了
I am forced to do so myself.
荣耀？
Honor?
所以Marcus Crassus的表亲才会他妈的
Is that why the cousin to Marcus Crassus lays dead
死在我们的房里了吗？
in our fucking house?
并非我本意
Was not my intent.
就算是本意也没关系了
Your intent matters for nothing.
哦 操！
Oh fuck!
我们大祸临头了！
We are undone!
还没有
No.
Licinia一个人来的
Licinia came alone.
她没跟任何人说起过此行
She told no one of her purpose.
谁也没有？
No one?
连对她的奴隶都没说
Not even her slaves.
只要处理掉尸体
There is nothing to connect her
她和Batiatus家族…
with the House of Batiatus…
就再无任何瓜葛
once the body is disposed of.
Ilithyia怎么办？
What of Ilithyia?
哦 交给我来处理吧
Oh, I'll take care of her.
向你道歉 让你与Glaber的妻子交欢
Apologies, It was an unfortunate mistake,
完全是个很不幸的错误
coupling you with Glaber's wife.
这并非我本意 我也不知道
Know that it was not my intent, nor of my knowledge.
应该是我道歉才对
It is I that owes apology.
一时之间 我的手不再属于自己
For a moment my hands were not my own,
而属于那个不复存在的人了
but those of a man who no longer exists.
那我们就再别说起今晚了
Let us not speak of this night again.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus.
你的忠诚
Your loyalty.
为训练场争得了荣耀
It honors this ludus.
我不是有意的…
I did not mean…
是啊 当然你并非本意
No, course you didn't.
她取笑我的样子…
The way she laughed at me…
你告诉我 是跟Crixus上床的
You said I was to lie with Crixus.
你为什么要给我斯巴达克斯？
Why did you give me Spartacus?
你为什么要这么做？
Why would you do such a thing?
你心知肚明
You ask what you already know answer to.
我丈夫会因此羞愧死的…
My husband will see me dead for this…
你杀死了我…
You have killed me…
还没呢
No.
我只是把我们拉得更近了
I have brought us closer.
没人会知道今晚发生了什么
No one will ever know what happened here tonight.
Licinia的尸体永不会被发现
Licinia's body will never be found.
你很安全
You're protected.
不安全
No.
他们终将知道
They will know.
他们会从我眼中看到实情
They will see the deed in my eyes.
那你就跟我呆在一起
Then you'll stay here with me.
直到你眼里一切澄明
Until your eyes are clear.
不论怎样掩饰 我们之间都存有差异
We've had our differences, however veiled.
但我终于知道了 你是个多么有价值的朋友啊
But I've come to see what a valuable friend you are.
这将是我们之间的小秘密
This will be our little secret.